Joanna Douba UI/UX Designer Web Developer

<u>LinkedIn Profile</u> <u>behance.net/joannadouba</u>

Ottawa, ON +1 (819) 355-4555 joanna@jabak.ca "When I contact Joanna I know the job will be done perfectly. I'm always in safe hands, she is quick in action and response and a great problem solver! Joanna, is constantly in touch with latest trends of web design and technology, her advice and consultation makes the idea much stronger and friendly for the project." — Najla AlBassam, Founder & CEO at Haya Design Studio

"When we set out to develop and launched a new website for Muse Films, Joanna was instrumental in enhancing the website. She understood the brief as required and quickly set out to create a clean and professional design on WordPress. I found her to be reliable, accountable, a good communicator and is quality driven. I enjoyed and highly recommend working with Joanna." – Dalyah Bakheet, Founder at Muse Films

Executive Summary

As an experienced web developer and digital media production specialist with over 14 years of experience, I excel at conceptualizing, creating and managing large-scale projects from start to finish.

I have 6 years of experience in designing and developing full-stack websites as well as custom themes, customizing existing themes, and integrating and creating plugins using WordPress, Laravel, and other technologies.

Throughout my career, I have employed critical thinking & creative problem-solving to break down complex mega-projects into achievable tasks; This enabled me to successfully lead & deliver projects worth over \$7 million USD for Fortune 500 clients.

Education

- Interactive Media Management, Algonquin College of Applied Arts and Technology | 2017
- Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design, American University of Beirut | 2009

Skills

- Proficient in Adobe Creative Suite including Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Lightroom, Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Audition, Adobe Lightroom, Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Animate, Google Web Designer
- Intermediate knowledge of HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, jQuery, WordPress, InVision App, Bootstrap, PHP, MySQL, TailwindCSS, Git, GitHub, Docker, Shopify

Professional Experience

Professor | Algonquin College of Applied Arts and Technology | Jan. 2020 – Present

- Taught courses in Web Development, Web Design, and Client Projects focused on developing handson skills to plan and develop websites, online media, and dynamic content through HTML, CSS,
 JavaScript, PHP, WordPress Theme Development. The courses also tackle color theory, component
 and page UI and layout design, the creative process, and responsive web design through a mobile-first
 methodology. Whereas in the Client Projects course, students conceptualized, designed, and developed
 a multimedia project for their respective clients.
- Developed a new project-based curriculum for the web design and development courses to integrate the learning objectives carried out through a series of mini-projects that compile into one complete real-world capstone project submitted at the end of the term.

Web Designer and Developer | Terabit | Dec. 2020 – June 2022

Worked remotely independently and with a small team and on project planning and designing websites and apps for various clients. Used creative design skills in designing wireframes and prototypes for

websites and apps. Led creative teams to deliver project requirements. Gathered client briefs and developed mood boards. Designed prototypes and tested them using Adobe Xd. Developed websites using PHP, CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, iQuery, WordPress CMS, and Laravel Framework

eLearning Project Manager | Terabit | Sept. 2019 – Dec. 2019

Sourced talent to produce a 3-module eLearning course over the span of 8 weeks. Gathered client briefs and developed mood boards. Supervised and managed talent to produce eLearning storyboards, graphics, as well as the full course using Articulate Storyline. Led creative teams to deliver project requirements. Directed talking-head videos using a local actor

Web Designer and Developer | Freelance | May 2017 – Present

- Developed mood boards, gathered client briefs. Designed prototypes and tested them using Invision
 App. Developed webpages and websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript as well as WordPress as
 the content management system. Prepared social media posts, scheduled, and posted them for clients.
 Managed website hosting and domain name registration for clients.
- **Notable work** includes the websites for boutique Saudi graphic design studio <u>Haya Design Studio</u> and boutique animation production company *Muse Films*, which involved gathering client briefs, helping them select the WordPress theme best-suited to their needs to buy based on their individual tastes. Setting up each client on their own hosting solution, transferring domain names to client accounts. Installing WordPress, along with the chosen themes and plugins to cover back up, security, and additional frontend features. Customizing their look and feel using CSS and PHP. Preparing training documents to educate the clients on how to update their own websites using the WordPress back end.

Media Production Manager | Alwasaet | Jul. 2015 – Oct. 2016

Creatively directed as well as managed the development, production and delivery of 100 bi-lingual (English & Arabic) educational 2D animation episodes x 3.5 – 7 min each for Saudi Aramco's King Abdulaziz Center for World Culture, as well as animations for several other clients. This project was worth \$5 million (USD).

Project Coordinator | Alwasaet | May 2014 – Jun. 2015

- Managed the development, production and delivery of an additional 100 bi-lingual (English & Arabic) educational 2D animation episodes x 3.5 7 min each for Saudi Aramco's King AbdulAziz Center for World Culture, as well as animations for several other clients. This project was worth \$5 million (USD).
- Designed and implemented Alwasaet's website using self-hosted WordPress (still currently in use).

Graphic Designer | Cubic Connect | Jul. 2012 – Apr. 2014

- Conceptualized and developed the business case for white-label cross-platform Mobile and Smart
 TV applications to be sold to telecom operators and TV channels. Designed the UX / UI for these
 applications. Collaborated closely with the technical team to deliver beta and alpha versions of the
 applications.
- **Designed promotional material** for the company, including booklets, posters, roll-ups, etc.
- Conceptualized and successfully pitched a mobile application similar to My Talking Tom™ called <u>Wisso</u> with three original typical Lebanese characters to Nokia (Lebanon Branch) in partnership with FOO Solutions as the mobile development arm. Creatively directed and managed the entire production process to deliver all digital assets to FOO Solutions for mobile development.

Business Plan Development / Graphic Designer | Media Link International | Jan. 2012 – Jun. 2012

• Researched and presented a business plan for the development of a video-on-demand platform for Arabic content. Developed a marketing strategy and material to sell the platform as a service to

- telecom and media companies and institutions.
- **Designed the front-end UX & UI** for the platform. Developed the platform's corporate identity. **Designed promotional material** for the company, including booklets, posters, roll-ups, etc.

Project Coordinator | AdEyes Animation Studio | Nov. 2010 - Dec. 2011

- Successfully managed the production and delivery of a 3D cartoon animation series (15 ep. x 15 min each) in Arabic based on the immensely popular social satire TV Series, Tash Ma Tash, after joining the company in the middle of the project lifecycle, when no animation had been delivered thus far. This project was a \$2.25 million (USD) project.
- 13 Episodes posted on YouTube, with all series episodes having reached over 596 million views cumulatively.

Junior Graphic Designer | TAGBrands | Aug. 2010 - Oct. 2010

Designed and produced graphics for Abu Dhabi Islamic Bank including UI/UX for their ATM machine.

Junior Graphic Designer | Graphic Shop | Apr. 2010 – Jun. 2010

Managed communications with, designed and produced graphics for Mövenpick Hotel Beirut.

Project Coordinator / Computer Graphics Artist | 2Digital Productions | Sep. 2009 – Mar. 2010

- Coordinated the production of a 3D live entertainment show starring the famous Arabic comic book character Maiid.
- Implemented 3D Modeling and texturing for the show.

Notable Clients

- Children's Hospital of East Ontario (CHEO)
- Envirocentre
- Algonquin College
- Media Club of Ottawa
- MBC Group (Midde East Broadcasting Corporation)
- Abu Dhabi Media Group
- Audi
- Mövenpick Hotels & Resorts

- STC (Saudi Telecom Company)
- Zain Telecom Company
- King Abdulaziz Center for World Culture
- Saudi Aramco
- King Abdulaziz City for Science and Technology
- The National Center for Performance Measurement – Saudi Arabia
- Nokia
- Abu Dhabi Islamic Bank